Welcome to our overview of Amazon's multiple accounts policy.
This video shows you how to remain compliant with multiple selling accounts and effectively
manage your businesses in the Amazon store.
First, let's discuss the multiple accounts policy.
Amazon's policy is that sellers can have one account per seller per region unless they
have a legitimate business need for opening a second account, in which case all accounts
must be kept in good standing.
You're considered as having multiple or related accounts when you own, operate, are involved
with or have access to more than one Amazon selling account.
Here are three examples of legitimate business reasons for maintaining multiple accounts.
One, when you have more than one brand, each with a different storefront name, you can
open a separate selling account for each brand to simplify maintenance.
For example, if you've registered a brand that sells soap and also registered a brand
that sells pet food, you can open two separate accounts.
Two, when you manufacture products for two distinct and separate companies, you can open
a separate selling account for each to help streamline your different accounts.
For example, if you manufacture soaps for company A and are going to start manufacturing
soaps for company B, you can open two separate selling accounts.
Three, when you're enrolled in an Amazon program that requires separate accounts.
Note that you don't need approval to open a second account, but Amazon may act if you
don't comply with the policy.
Your other accounts may be affected if you operate more than one and violate Amazon selling
policies or the seller code of conduct in any of your accounts.
Amazon could cancel listings, suspend or deactivate accounts or suspend or forfeit payments.
To understand each of the points of the seller code of conduct, visit the respective page
related to your regional Amazon store.
Search "seller code of conduct" in Seller Central for more information.
You'll receive a notification on your account health page, which can be accessed via the
Seller Central main menu's performance section if you violate this or other Amazon selling
policies.
Now, let's look at two examples of account impact after a policy violation.
In the first, a seller has two Amazon selling accounts because he's registered two separate
brands.
He operates a storefront for his soaps and one for his pet food and the account for soaps
receives a warning about manipulating sales rank.
In this case, he must heed the warning and remedy any issue with that brand in a timely
manner before it affects his pet food brand.
In the second, a seller receives an account deactivation notice for manipulating sales
rank in her account for selling soaps.
Her pet food account will also be deactivated because the two are related to her overall
selling account.
The account for the soap brand will need to be reinstated before her other accounts can
be active again.
For more information on Amazon's multiple accounts policy, including how to respond to
a violation notice, visit Seller Central and search "selling policies" and "seller code
of conduct" on the main page.
To learn how to reactivate your selling account, watch our video "address a multiple account
policy violation" in Seller University.
This concludes our training on how to comply with Amazon's multiple accounts policy.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon store!